const questions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "What is React?",
    options: [
      "A JavaScript library",
      "A database",
      "A browser",
      "An operating system"
    ],
    answer: "A JavaScript library"
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "React is mainly used to build?",
    options: [
      "User Interfaces",
      "Servers",
      "Databases",
      "Games"
    ],
    answer: "User Interfaces"
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "Who developed React?",
    options: [
      "Google",
      "Facebook",
      "Microsoft",
      "Amazon"
    ],
    answer: "Facebook"
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "What is JSX?",
    options: [
      "JavaScript XML",
      "Java Syntax",
      "JSON File",
      "Java Code"
    ],
    answer: "JavaScript XML"
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "Which hook is used to manage state?",
    options: [
      "useEffect",
      "useState",
      "useRef",
      "useMemo"
    ],
    answer: "useState"
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "Which hook is used for side effects?",
    options: [
      "useState",
      "useEffect",
      "useMemo",
      "useReducer"
    ],
    answer: "useEffect"
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "Props are used to?",
    options: [
      "Pass data between components",
      "Store database",
      "Style components",
      "Create server"
    ],
    answer: "Pass data between components"
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: "React components must return?",
    options: [
      "HTML",
      "JSX",
      "JSON",
      "CSS"
    ],
    answer: "JSX"
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "Virtual DOM improves?",
    options: [
      "Security",
      "Performance",
      "Database speed",
      "Network speed"
    ],
    answer: "Performance"
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "Which function is used to create React app root in React 18?",
    options: [
      "ReactDOM.render()",
      "createRoot()",
      "renderApp()",
      "mountRoot()"
    ],
    answer: "createRoot()"
  } 
];

export default questions;
